In this lecture, we're going to learn about Amazon bedrock intelligent prompt routing.
So, Amazon bedrock intelligent prompt routing, dynamically routes requests between foundation
models from the same family, optimizing for response, quality and cost.
Right now, it supports models from entropic, so you can see all the models from entropic
that it supports, then it supports models from metallama, so some small language models
with 8 billion parameters and then some models with 90 billion and 70 billion parameters.
It also supports Amazon nova, so it supports nova light and nova pro, now just remember
that since nova light is a much smaller model, so it's good at simpler task, but more importantly
it's going to be cost effective and there's going to be less latency compared to nova
pro.
So, I've just added a price comparison chart here between nova light and nova pro,
so if you see the pricing for Amazon nova to light, so price per thousand tokens and thousand
tokens are about 750 words, so price per 750 words is dollar 0.000525, now if I take
a look at the Amazon nova to pro and again per thousand input tokens is dollar 0.0021 875, so
that means it's almost 4 times more expensive than nova light, now let's go and understand
how bedrock intelligent problem routing helps us in cost optimization through intelligent
routing.
So, let's go ahead and try and understand this through an example, let's say you have built
a generative AI application using nova light and nova pro, now let's assume that the end
user has sent a query which says summarize this paragraph in one sentence and then he provides
the paragraph, so what the bedrock intelligent problem router is going to do, since it's
a simpler task it's going to route it to the Amazon nova light, because it's cheaper
and there's going to be less latency, now let's take another scenario, this time the
user says analyze these logs and identify the root cause of cascading failures across distributed
manufacturing systems, now here the LLM has to analyze the logs and identify the root cause,
so it's a much more complex task, and this time most likely over bedrock intelligent
problem router is going to send that request to nova pro, now you might say that for every
task there is going to be some quality difference between the two models because one is
a much larger model and another one is smaller, and in that scenario so bedrock intelligent
problem router allows you to define that threshold on the quality difference of the response
between the two models, so now let's say in the first scenario once the request is sent
to a generative AI application, the bedrock intelligent problem router is going to evaluate
the response both from nova light and nova pro, and now let's say it determines that
the difference in the quality is just 4% and your threshold was 5% so it's going to route
it to nova light, but if it determines let's say in the second scenario the threshold
is 32% then it's going to route to Amazon nova pro, so that's how intelligent problem
routing can help you cost optimize, okay so that's pretty much it from this lecture,
I'll see you in the next lecture, thank you.